要记得
Remember.
我爱你
I love you.
我爱你 托马斯
I love you, Thomas.
妈妈
Mom!
托马斯 没事的
Thomas, it's okay.
托马斯
Thomas!
不要
No !!!
托马斯
Thomas!
起来 我们要走了  来吧
Wake up, we got to go! Come on!
我们走  我们要走了 快
Let's go! Move, we got to go!
等等...
Wait, wait, wait...!
你去哪里  我们没时间了
Where're you going! We don't have time!
- 来吧   - 来吧 我们走吧
- Come on!  - Come on, let's go.
离开这里
Get out of here!
有敌人  守卫防线
Breaks! Make breaks!
- 我们一定要走了  - 你在这里不安全的
- We got to move.  - You're not safe out here.
好了小孩们 我们走吧  快走
Alright, kids, let's go. Let's go! Move it!
一直走  不要停
Keep moving.  Keep moving.
带他们离开  快
Help them take off! Quick!
移动迷宫：焦土试炼
你们还好吗
You kids doing alright?
很抱歉所有的大惊小怪  我们有点太兴奋
Sorry about all the fuss. We have ourselves a bit of a swarm.
你是谁
Who are you?
我是你们还活着的原因  让你们活着也是我的目的
I'm the reason you're all still alive. It's my intention to keep you that way.
现在跟我来吧  我们会带你们去走走
Now, come with me. We'll get you kids squared away.
你们可以叫我詹森先生  这地方是由我来负责的
You can call me Mr. Janson. I run this place.
对我们来说这是个避难所 不受外面恐怖的世界侵害
For us, it's a sanctuary, safe from the horrors of the outside world.
你们都应该把这当作是一个小站
You all should think of it as a way station.
就像家跟家之间  自己小心
Kind of a home between homes. Watch yourselves
而你是带我们回家的
And then you're taking us home?
各种各样的家
A home of sorts.
不幸的是无论你来自哪里都没多少人生存了
Sadly there wouldn't be much left of wherever you came from.
但我们有一个适合你们的地方 在外面焦土的一个避难所
But we do have a place for you, a refuge, outside the Scorch,
一个WCKD永远也不会找到你们的地方  这听起来怎么样
where WCKD will never find you again. How does that sounds?
为什么你要帮我们
Why are you helping us?
我们就说这世界在一个相当危险的形势吧
Let's just say the world out is in a rather precarious situation.
我们都吊在一条非常细的绳子上
We're all hanging on by a very thin thread.
事实上你们可以从闪焰病毒生存下来
The fact that you kids can survive the Flare virus
让你们成为人类继续生存的最好机会
makes you the best chance of humanity's continue survival.
不幸的是这同时也让你们成为目标
Unfortunately, it also makes you a target.
毫无疑问你们现在已经注意到了
There's no doubt by now you've noticed.
越过这门就是你们新生活的开始
Beyond this door, lies the beginning of your new lives.
第一件事
First things first.
就让我们先解决体味的问题
Let's do something about that smell.
爽
Great.
- 这是什么  - 只是一支小鸡尾酒
- What is that?  - Just a little cocktail.
盖 叶酸 苯酚A到Z
Calcium, folic, pheno A to Z,
几乎都是你在外面一直缺少的营养
pretty much everything you've been deprived of out there.
尽量放松
Try to relax.
你确定你取够血了吗
Sure you get enough of that?
- 晚上好 克劳福德医生  - 晚上好
- Good evening, Dr. Crawford.  - Good evening.
- 新来的人适应的怎么样  - 目前来说还不错
- How're the new arrivals holding up?  - So far so good.
好吧
Alright.
你一定是特丽莎了
You must Teresa.
托马斯
Thomas?
- 是  - 请跟我来
- Yeah?  - Come with me please.
托马斯 很感谢你来见我
Thomas, thank you for seeing me.
很抱歉麻烦到你 我只是希望我们...
Sorry for the inconvenience, I was just hoping we...
可以远离他们就我们两人谈谈
might get a moment to chat in private, away from the others.
那么...
Well...
我不会用你太多时间
I won't take up too much of your time.
那个我只有一个问题
Well, I only have one question:
你还记得WCKD些什么
What do you remember from WCKD;
你没有惹上麻烦
You're not in trouble.
我只是在谈谈  只是想搞清楚
I'm just having a conversation. I'm just trying to understand.
搞清楚什么
Understand what?
你是站在哪一边的
Whose side are you on.
我记得我以前是给WCKD工作的
I remember I used to work for WCKD.
我记得他们送我进迷宫
I remember they sent me into the maze.
我记得我看着我的朋友在我面前死
I remember watching my friends die in front of me.
我是他们那边的
I on their side.
有意思
Interesting.
你说你曾经为WCKD工作 但他们送你进迷宫
You say you worked for WCKD, but they sent you into the Maze.
为什么他们会这么做
Why would they do something like that?
我不知道  也许你应该在杀他们之前问他们
I don't know. Maybe you should ask them before you kill them all.
我会谨记这一点
I'll be sure to keep that in mind.
享受你在这里休息吧
Enjoy the rest of your stay.
就这样
That's it?
对 你已经说了所有我需要知道的了
Yeah, you've told me everything I need to know.
你和你的朋友都被清除了加入其他人
You and your friends have all been cleared to join the others.
很快你们会去到更绿的牧场
Soon you all will be moving on to greener pastures.
等等
Wait.
其他人
Others?
嘿 托马斯
Hey Thomas!
嘿 米诺怎么回事
Hey, Minho What's going on?
我们不是唯一的迷宫
We weren't the only Maze.
有一声巨大的爆炸  而这些人不知从哪里冒出来的
And there was this big loud explosion. And these guys came out of nowhere.
- 他们在那开始开枪扫射  - 这太惨烈了
- They started shooting up the place.  - It was intense.
- 他们把我们拉出迷宫然后带我们来这里  - 那其他人呢
- They pulled us off the Maze and brought us here.  - What about the rest?
其他留在迷宫里的人  他们怎么样了
The other people left behind in the Maze, what happened to them?
我不知道  我猜WCKD还留着他们
I don't know. I guess WCKD still has them.
- 你们在这多长时间了  - 没多久 只有1或2天
- How long you guy's been here?  - Not long , just a days or 2.
在那里的那个小孩他在这里最久
That kid over there, He's been here the longest.
几乎一个星期了
Almost one week.
他的迷宫就只有女孩子
His Maze is nothing but girls.
真的吗
Really?
有些人就是运气好
Some guys has all the luck.
晚上好 先生们  女士们
Good evening, gentlemen. Ladies.
你们知道该怎么做  如果你听到你的名字
You all know how this works. If you heard your name called
请有序的站起来然后来我身后的同事这边...
please rise in an orderly fashion and join my colleagues...
他们会护送你们去东翼
behind me where they will escort you to the eastern wing.
你们的新生活即将开始
Your new lives are about to begin.
康纳
Connor.
艾德琳
Adeline.
贾斯廷
Justin.
彼得
Peter.
艾丽森
Alison.
史昆纪
Squeegee.
好了 安静下来
Alright, settle down.
富兰克林和阿比盖尔
Franklin and Abigail.
现在  你们不要灰心  如果我可以带更多的人 我会的
Now, now. Don't get discouraged. If I could take more, I would.
每天都有机会
There's always tomorrow.
会轮到你们的
Your time will come.
继续吃饭吧
Go on, eat up.
他们要去哪里
Where are they going?
远离这里
Far from here.
这些混蛋真幸运
Lucky bastard.
类似农场的地方  一个安全的地方
Some kind of farm. A safe place.
他们一次只能带你们几个人去
They can only take in a couple of you at a time.
嘿 特丽莎
Hey, Teresa.
特丽莎
Teresa!
嘿  嘿  嘿
Hey. Hey hey hey.
他们要带她去哪里
Where're they taking her?
就多做几个测试  别担心 他们很快就好了
Just have to run a few more tests. Don't worry, they will be done with her soon.
她还好吗
Is she okay?
她没事
She's fine.
我要上铺
I'll have top bunk.
太慢了
Too slow.
我可以习惯这个的
I could get used to this.
这不算差啊
Yeah, it's not bad.
你觉得这些人想从特丽莎身上得到什么
What do you think those guys want with Teresa?
我知道这女孩的一件事是她能照顾好自己的
And if there is one thing I know about that girl, is she can take care of herself.
不用担心
Don't worry about it.
下面
Down here.
来吧  跟我来
Come on. Follow me.
什么
What?
快点  这边
Hurry. This way.
来吧
Come on.
嘿 等一下  我们在干什么
Hey, wait a second. What the hell are we doing?
来吧 我们要错过了
Come on, we're going to miss it.
我他妈的在干什么
What the hell am I doing?
我们在这干什么
What are we doing here?
过来这里
Come here.
看
Watch.
这他妈的是什么
What the hell was that?
他们每天晚上都带一个新的进来
They bring in new ones every night.
- 那他们对他们做什么  - 我不知道
- And what do they do with them?  - I don't know.
这是我能去到最远的地方了 排气管没通往那部分
This is as far as I've gotten here The vents didn't go into that section.
但自从他们进去后他们就没再出来了
But once they go through that door, they don't come back out.
我认为从来没有人可以离开这地方
I don't think anybody ever leave this place.
来吧 我们要在有人发觉我们不见了之前回去
Come on, we got to go before someone noticed we're gone.
你为什么给我看这个
And why do you show me this?
因为也许其他人会听你的
Because maybe the others will listen to you.
这里有些怪异的事情而我知道你也是这么认为的
There's something weird going on here and I know you think so too.
嘿 等等
Hey, wait.
- 你叫什么名字  - 阿里斯
- What's your name?  - Aris.
阿里斯
Alice.
巴里
Barry.
沃尔特
Walt.
埃德加
Edgar.
- 萨曼莎  - 我想知道那门后是通往什么地方的
- Samantha.  - I want to know what's through that door.
亚伦
Aaron.
不 我们已经讨论过这个了
No, we've been over this.
你说他们被遮盖了 所以你不知道你看见的是什么
You said they were covered up, so you don't know what you saw.
这可以是任何东西
It could be anything like that.
我知道我看见的是什么  他们是身体
I know exactly what I saw. They were bodies.
阿里斯说他们每天晚上都带一批新的进去
Aris say they bring in a new batch every night.
他妈的阿里斯是谁啊
Who the hell is Aris?
亨利
Henry.
提姆
Tim.
好吧
Well.
你哭了吗
Are you sobbed?
还有最后一个但这不重要 大卫
And last but not least, David.
谢谢你们的注意  享受你们剩余的晚上
Thank you for your attention. Enjoy the rest of your evening.
好了  直到我们知道这是什么事之前
Okay. Until we know where this thing ends,
我们应该低调别引起任何注意 好吗
we should just keep our heads down and try not to draw any attention to ourselves, alright?
- 他在干什么  - 我觉得他在引起注意
- What is he doing?  - I think he is drawing attention to himself.
等一下  你没有被叫上
Whoa, hang on. You weren't called.
- 我就进去一下  - 这是限制区域
- I'm just going to be a second.  - This is a restricted area.
我只是想去见我的朋友 你能让我过去吗
I just want to see my friend, can you let me through?
回到你的位置上
Get your ass back in that chair..
- 你们怎么回事  - 滚回去
- What's your problem, man?  - Back off!
- 为什么你们不让人通过  - 控制好你的朋友
- Why won't you let through?  - Take control of your friend!
这里发生什么事
What's happening here?
托马斯 我认为我们可以互相信任
Thomas, thought we could trust each other.
你知道我们在这是一伙的
You know we're on the same team here.
是吗
Are we?
带他们去他们的房
Get them to their bunks.
你们全部进去
Get in! All of you!
刚才那是怎么回事
Why the hell was that about?
你不是真认为他们会就这样让你过去吧
You don't really think they were just going to let you through?
不 当然不会
No, of course I didn't.
不
No.
我要找出门的另一边是什么
I'm going to find out what's on the other side of that door.
好吧
Alright.
听着  他们在隐藏了些东西
Look. They're hiding something.
好吗 这些人不是像他们说的那样子的
Okay, these people are not who they say they are.
不 托马斯你根本不知道
No, Thomas, you don't know that.
唯一我们知道是他们把我们从WCKD那救了出来
The only thing that we do know is that they helped rescued us from WCKD.
他们给我们新衣服 给我们食物 给我们正常的床
They gave us new clothes, they gave us food, they gave us a proper bed.
我们有些人很长时间没有的东西
Some of us haven't had that in a long time.
- 是 但你...  - 我们有些人比其他人更长时间
- Yeah, but you...  - Some of us are a lot longer than others.
- 嘿 托马斯  - 搞什么...
- Hey, Thomas.  - What the...
- 你拿到了 对吧  - 这小孩是谁
- You get it, right?  - Who is this kid?
对 我们出发吧
Yeah, let's go.
听着 也许你们是对的 也许我只是有妄想症
Look, maybe you guys are right, maybe I'm just being paranoid,
但我要去确认一下
But I got to find out for sure.
就给我掩护  我会尽快回来
Just cover for me. I'll be back as soon as I can.
特丽莎
Teresa?
是瑞秋
It's Rachel.
他们在第一晚就带走她了
They took her the first night.
我跟她说过会没事的
I told her it's going to be okay.
你确定这不能再等了吗
You sure this can't wait?
她很明确 长官  她要你亲自跟她谈谈
She was very specific, sir. She wanted to talk with you personally.
好像我没能力处理好似的
As if I don't have enough to deal with.
就...等我一下
Just... bear with me.
我们再受到风暴的干扰
We are getting some interference from the storm.
来吧 这够好了 快连接吧
Come on, it's good enough, make the connection.
晚上好 佩姬博士  很高兴再见到你
Good evening, Dr. Paige. Lovely to see you again.
虽然我承认我...我没有料到这么快收到你的消息
Although I admit I... I wasn't expecting to hear from you quite so soon.
计划有变 詹森
Change of plans, Janson.
我会比预期早一点到 就明天
I will be arriving a little sooner than expected, first thing tomorrow.
噢  你能来我们会很高兴的
Oh! We'll be delighted to have you.
我想你会对我们取得的进展感到满意的
I think you'll be pleased with the progress we've made.
正如你所见 前期的成果都是非常有前途的
As you can see, earlier results have been extremely promising.
无论你在那里对他们做的是什么 这已经有效了
Whatever it is you've been doing to them in there, it's working.
还不够好
Not well enough.
我刚收到董事会的批准
I just received Board approval.
我要所有剩下的研究对像进入昏迷状态和准备收割
I want all the remaining subjects sedated and prep for harvest
我在到达前做好
by the time I arrive.
佩奇博士 我们会尽快完成的
Doctor Paige, we're going as fast as we can.
- - 我们还在测试中  - 做得再快点
- We are still running tests.  - Try something faster.
知道我能保证他们安全这是最好的计划
Until I can guarantee their security, this is the best plan.
长官女士 安全是我的工作  我们这是24小时封锁的
Ma'am, security is my job. We're on 24 hour lock down here.
我向你保证实验体都是安全的
I am assuring you, the assets are secure.
你找到右臂了吗
Have you found the Right Arm?
还没有
Not yet.
我们一直在山上跟踪他们
We tracked them as far as the mountains.
那么他们还在外面
So they're still out there.
而且他们已经打击了我们2个设施
And they've already hit 2 of our installations.
他们跟我们一样都想要这些小孩
They want these kids, as badly as we do,
而我不能... 我不能再承受其他损失了
and I cannot... I cannot afford another loss.
起码不能在我接近成功研制出解药时
Not now, when I'm so close to a cure.
如果你不能完成任务 我会另找其人
If you're not up to the task, I'll find someone who is.
没这个必要
That won't be necessary.
我建议我们从最近的新人开始
I would suggest we start with the most recent arrivals.
就快去完成它
Just get it done!
詹森
Janson.
我不想他们感觉到任何痛苦
I don't want them to feel any pain.
他们什么都感觉不了
They won't feel a thing.
托马斯
Thomas!
- 我们要走了  - 干什么
- We got to go.  - What's up?
我们要走了 马上  来吧
We got to go. We got to go, right now! Come on!
- 你在说什么  - 你说我们要走了是什么意思
- What the hell are you talking about?  - What do you mean we got to go?
你们必须要来  来吧 我们要走了
You're coming. Come on, we got to go.
来吧  他们要找我们了
Come on. They're coming for us!
- 在那里发生什么事  - 阿里斯 发生什么事
- What happened in there?  - Aris, what happened?
托马斯 你能冷静下来跟我们说吗
Thomas, can you just calm down and talk to us.
- 她还活着  - 她是谁
- She's still alive.  - Who's she?
- 特丽莎  - 艾娃  艾娃
- Teresa?  - Ava. Ava.
艾娃
Ava?
你能转过身来跟我们说吗
Would you just turn around and talk to us.
这是WCKD
It's WCKD!
这里还是WCKD  这一直都是WCKD
It's still WCKD. It's always been WCKD.
托马斯
Thomas.
你看见什么了
What did you see?
快来
Come on, come on, come on.
好了  我们走吧
Okay, let's go! Let's go!
你们快走 有些事我必须要去做
You guys go away, there's something I got to do.
- 你在说什么  - 相信我 这很重要
- What're you talking about?  - Trust me, it's important.
你们想离开这里 对吧  就快走吧
You guys want to get out of here, right?   Just go.
我跟他一起去
I'll go with him.
好的  温斯顿 走吧  来吧
Okay. Winston, go, go. Come on!
你确信我们能相信这孩子
You sure we can trust this kid?
你不会想知道你在外面是谁
You don't want to know who you'll be without.
你们在外面这干什么
What are you kids doing out?
我要封锁这里 叫所有人进来
I want this this place lock down, call everyone in.
除非死了不然任何人都不许离开
No one leaves unless everyone is accounted for.
- 如果你看到他们就告诉我  - 还在寻找
- Tell me if you got eyes on them.  - Still looking. Still looking.
来吧
Come on, come on, come on.
那里
There!
- 这是谁  - 克劳福德
- Who is that?  - Crawford.
他们在找那个女孩
They're going after the girl.
- 带所有人去中翼  - 是的 长官
- Get everyone to the med wing.  - Yes, sir!
我要他们活着
I want them alive!
别动  原地别动
Freeze! Stay where you are!
为什么他们会向我们开枪
Why are they shooting at us?
米诺  你他妈的在干什么
Minho. What the hell are you doing?
米诺
Minho!
草
Shit.
好了  我们走  来吧  我们走吧
Okay. Let's go. Come on. Let's go.
克劳福德博士  你来这里是... 等等 哇 哇
Dr. Crawford. Are you here to... Wait, whoa whoa.
- 好的 好的  - 她在哪
- Okay, okay!  - Where is she?
她在哪
Where is she?
- 蹲下  - 好的
- Get down!  - Alright.
特丽莎
Teresa.
- 退后  - 就跟他说的做
- Get back!  - Just do as he says.
- 他们对你做什么了  - 托马斯
- What did they do to you?  - Thomas.
把你的手给我
Give me your hands!
你们永远也逃不掉的
You're never going to get away with this.
发生什么事
What's going on?
我们要马上离开这里  马上 来吧
We're going to get out of here, right now. Right now, come on.
大伙 他们来了  我们该去哪
Guys, they're coming. Where do we go?
费平 让开
frypan, move.
回退  回退
Get back. Get back!
他们把门挡住了
They have the door barricade.
大伙  我们得离开这里
Guys. We got to get out of here!
我们该从哪走
Where do we go?
我们被困住了
We're seal in!
纽特  来帮忙
Newt. Help help help!
走 走 走
Go go go!
快点 快点 快点
Come on, come on, come on!
快点
Come on. Come on.
- 赶快来  - 快点
- Hurry! Go!  - Come on. Come on.
托马斯
Thomas!
我们走吧
Let's go!
站在我后面
Stay behind me.
我草
Oh, shit.
来吧
Come on!
就是这  就是这  快点
There it is. There it is  Come on.
草  别这样  不要...
Shit. Come on. No, no, no...!
托马斯
Thomas!
打开门 詹森
Open the door, Janson!
- 你真的不想我打开的  - 打开这该死的门
- You really don't want me to.  - Open the damn door!
听我说  我是想救你的命
Listen to me! I'm trying to save your life.
迷宫是一回事 但你们在焦土不会维持到1天的
The Maze is one thing, but you kids wouldn't last 1 day out in Scorch.
如果环境杀不死你 狂客会杀你们的
If the elements don't kill you,the Cranks will.
托马斯 你得相信我
Thomas, you have to believe me.
我只是为了你好
I only want what's best for you.
是啊 让我猜猜  WCKD是好的
Yeah, let me guess. WCKD is good?
你们不会通过那道门的 托马斯
You're not getting through that door, Thomas.
- 嘿 大伙  - 来吧
- Hey, guys.  - Come on!
托马斯 来吧  我们走
Thomas, come on! Let's go!
上 上 上  阻止他
Go go go. Stop him!
关上主走廊门
Shut the main corridor door!  Shut the main corridor door!
来吧
Come on!
- 跑啊  - 托马斯 快跑
- Run!  - Thomas, come on!
快来 托马斯
Come on, Thomas!
托马斯 怎么回事
Thomas, what's going on?
来吧
Come on.
你们疯了
You're insane.
来吧 托马斯 我们走吧  快来
Come on, Thomas, let's go! Come on!
来吧 继续跑
Come on, keep moving!
来吧  来吧
Come on. Come on.
来吧 来吧
Come on, come on!
来吧  继续跑
Come on, come on. Keep going!
来吧 快走  我们会在风暴里甩掉他们的
Come on, Go. Go, we'll lose them in the storm.
我可以看见他们在围墙这里
I can see them over here at the fence!
走 走 走  弯下腰
Go go go. Stay low! Stay low!
- 特丽莎等一下  我们要呆在一起   - 我觉得我们甩掉他们了
- Teresa, hang on.we stay toghter  - I think we lost them.
- 来吧 继续走  - 大家来吧  我们走
- Come on, keep going!  - Come on, guys. Let's go.
- 小心  - 我们到底在去哪里
- Watch out!  - Where are we even going?
来吧  来吧  来吧  这里
Come on. Come on. Come on. Over here!
- 来吧  - 特丽莎 等等
- Come on.  - Teresa, wait.
特丽莎
Teresa!
- 下来这里  - 好吧 来吧
- Get down here!  - Okay, come on.
进去
Get inside.
来吧 我们走  进去这里
Come on, let's go. Go. Here, get in.
我们走吧 大伙
Let's go, guys.
我们在哪里
Where the hell are we?
- 我们要走了  - 不
- We got to go.  - No.
- 听着 我们要继续走  - 托马斯 停下来
- Look, we got to go.  - Thomas, stop!
告诉我怎么回事
Tell me what's going on.
是WCKD
It's WCKD.
是WCKD  他们骗了我们 我们从来就没逃离过
It's WCKD.They lied to us, we never escaped.
吊在半空中的身体  太多了数不清
Mid air were strung bodies. Too many to count.
你是什么意思  尸体
What do you mean? Dead bodies?
不是 但他们也不是活的
No, but they weren't alive either.
他们把他们吊起来了
They have them strung up.
用管子穿过他们
With tubes coming out of them.
他们在...他们在流干
They're being... They're being drain.
我们的体内有WCKD想要的东西
There's something inside of us that WCKD wants.
一些在我门血液里的东西
Something in our blood.
所以我们要尽可能的离他们远点
So we have to get as far away from them as possible.
好吧
Okay.
那么计划是什么
So, what's the plan?
- 你有计划的 对吧  - 对
- You do have a plan, right?  - Yeah.
我们跟着你来到这里 托马斯
Well, we followed you out here, Thomas.
而现在你说你不知道我们在去哪
And now you're saying that you have no idea where we're going
或我们在干什么
or what we're doing?
等等  詹森说过些什么
Wait.  Janson said something
...关于有人藏在山里  类似反抗的人或军队
... about people hiding in the mountains. Some kind of resistance or army.
右臂
Right Arm.
右臂  如果他们真的跟WCKD对抗
Right Arm. If they're really against WCKD,
也许他们能帮我们
maybe they can help us.
人  在山里
People. In the mountains.
山里人这就是你的计划
Mountain people That's your plan?
这是我们唯一的机会
It's the only chance we have.
嘿 大伙  看看这个
Hey, guys. Check this out.
米诺 灯照过来
Minho, give me the light.
有人来过这里
Someone's been down here.
来吧  打门打开
Come on. Open up.
看起来像有人生活在这里
Looks like people lived here.
而他们现在去哪里了
And where are they now?
我们拿点这些东西
Let's pack some of this stuff up.
任何你觉得可能需要的
Anything you think you might need.
我们分开走  看看还能找到什么  再回这里会合
We'll split up. See what else we can find. Meet back here .
等等 托马斯
Wait, Thomas.
我们走吧
Let's go.
- 托马斯  - 是
- Thomas.  - Yeah.
我们抛在身后留在那里的孩子...
All those kids we left behind back there...
我不想像他们那样结束生命
I do not want to end up like that.
嘿
Hey.
你有听我说吗
Do you hear me?
- 有 我听到了  - 很好
- Yeah, I hear you.  - Good.
我们在这找什么
Hell,  What are we looking for out here?
生命迹象  人
Signs of life. People.
生存者  任何能帮我们的人
Survivors. Anyone who can help us.
他算不算
Does he count?
草
Shit.
他们有电源
They have power.
你还好吗
You alright?
我没事
I'm fine.
什么
What?
你去哪了
Where did you go?
这看起来还可以用
This looks promising.
嘿  米诺 等等
Hey. Minho, wait!
托马斯 小心
Thomas, watch out!
- 后退  后退   - 天啊
- Get back. Get back. Get back.  - Jesus.
天啊
Christ!
噢
Oh!
哇  这他妈的是什么
Whoa. What the hell is that thing?
小心
Look out!
我们要走了  快
We got to move. We got to move. Go!
- 顶住  - 什么
- Hold it down!  - What?
顶住
Hold it down.
米诺 你在干什么
Minho, what are you doing?
小心
Watch out!
好了  快跑  快跑
Okay. Go go go. Go go!
我们快离开这里
Let's get the hell out of here!
草
Shit.
- 怎么回事  - 我不知道
- Whats going on?  - I don't know.
嘿
Hey!
嘿  快跑
Hey! Run!
快跑
Run!
草
Shit!
嘿
Hey!
来吧  离开这里
Come on! Get out of here!
- 离开  - 来吧
- Get out!  - Come on!
我们快跑
Let's go go go!
我们走吧
Let's go.
托马斯 米诺  这些是什么鬼东西
Thomas, Minho. What the hell are those things?
我不知道  就继续跑吧
I don't know! Just keep going!
快跑  快跑
Move! Move!
跟上  快来
Keep up! Come on.
我们快跑
Let's go.
草
Shit!
噢  不 不 不
Oh. No no no.
- 阿里斯 不要  - 不
- Aris, no!  - No!
特丽莎
Teresa!
米诺 来吧
Minho, come on!
来吧  快跑
Come on. Come on.
我们该去哪里
Where are we going to go?
我们得找到离开这里的方法
We got to find a way out of here!
快跑
Go!
- 纽特  - 纽特
- Newt!  - Newt!
- 纽特 你...你没事吧  - 没事
- Newt, you-you good?  - Yeah.
谢谢 托马斯
Thanks, Tommy!
- 来吧  - 来吧 纽特
- Come on!  - Come on, Newt!
穿过这里  穿过这里  我么走吧  他们来了
Through here! Through here! Let's go! They're coming!
天啊  我们在去哪里
Christ. Where are we going?
- 跟上 快点  - 来吧
- Keep it up! Go, go!  - Come on.
- 继续走  - 快点 他们来了
- Keep going!  - Come on, they're coming!
这是条死路
It's a dead end!
快带我们离开这里 托马斯
Get us out of here, Thomas!
这边  撞啊
This way! Go!
我拖延他们
I'll hold them back!
大力点
Harder!
快把门打开
Get the door open!
来吧 门开了
Come on, it's open!
快点  快点
Come on! Come on, come on, come on!
快点
Come on!
- 放开我  救命啊  - 拉
- Get off me! Help!  - Pull!
用力拉
Pull!
继续拉
Keep pulling.
快跑
Go go go!
- 快点  - 我们快走
- Hurry!  - Let's go!
- 米诺 走吧  我随后就来  - 快跑 快跑
- Minho, go. I'm right behind you.  - Let's go, let's go!
嘿  快离开这里
Hey. Hey. Hey!  Get out of here!
他们消失了吗
Are they're gone.
对  我们目前安全
Yeah. We're safe, for now.
我们应该继续走
We should get moving.
我们快收拾好东西
Let's pack it up.
阿里斯 来吧
Aris, come on.
弗赖伊  温斯顿  我们出发了
Fry. Winston. Let's go.
嘿 兄弟  你还好吗
Hey, man. You okay?
这地方发生什么事了
What the hell happen to this place?
我不知道
I don't know.
这看起来不像有人在这很长时间了
It doesn't look like anyone's been here in a long time.
希望全世界都不像这里吧
Hope the whole world is not like this.
哇 等一下  停下来
Whoa, hang on. Stop.
你们听到了吗
Did you hear that?
蹲下  所有人藏起来  藏起来
Get down! Everybody hide! Hide! Hide!
进去这里  进去
Get in here. In here. In here.
他们永远也不会停止寻找我们 是吗
They are never going to stop looking for us, are they?
大家都没事吧
Everyone good?
就差一点 伙计们
A little further, guys.
一定是这些山了
Those mountains. It's got to be it.
这是我们要去的地方
That's where we're going.
这很远
It's a long way out.
所以我们最好继续走
Then we better get moving.
温斯顿  嘿 温斯顿
Winston! Hey, Winston.
温斯顿
Winston!
- 温斯顿  - 他伤得很严重
- Winston!  - He's hurt pretty bad.
我们该做什么
What do we do?
温斯顿 你能听到我说话吗
Winston, can you hear me?
- 他还好吗  - 不
- Is he okay?  - No.
支持住 温斯顿
Hang in there, Winston.
- 托马斯  - 抬起他的脚
- Thomas.  - Grab his leg.
我抬起了
I got them. I got them.
我们得找到避难所
We got to find shelter.
看起来他们越来越近了
Looks like they are getting further away.
我们只要继续走  我们能做到的
We just got to keep moving. We can make it.
这看起来怎么样
How's it looking?
有点远
It's a little further.
这安慰不了人啊
That's not very convincing.
嘿 你发生什么事了
Hey, what's going on with you?
他们对我做了些事
They did something to me.
一开始我只是感觉我像从梦中或什么的醒来
At first I just felt like I was waking up from a dream or something.
然后他们就开始回来了
And then they all started coming back.
你的记忆
Your memory?
你记得些什么
What do you remember?
我记得他们第一次带你来的时候
I remember the first time they brought you in.
我是比你高的  而且更快
I was taller than you then. And faster.
好吧
Okay.
我记得我们为什么在那里
I remember why we were there.
我们以为我们能修复这一切
We thought we could fix all this.
我觉得我们应该回去
I think we should go back.
- 什么  - 就...就听我说吧
- What?  - Just-Just listen to me.
你在说什么  回去  在经过所有他们对我们做的事后
What are you talking about? Go back? After everything they've done to us?
- 不是那么简单的  - 不 我觉得就这么简单
- It's not that simple.  - Yeah, I think it is that simple.
不  你不明白
No. You don't understand.
什么  我不明白什么
What. What don't I understand?
本来一切都很好 直到你...
Everything was fine, until you...
什么
What?
没什么
Nothing.
特丽莎 你在告诉我什么
Teresa, what aren't you telling me?
- 嘿  伙计们 下来这里  - 我的天
- Hey! Guys, come down here!  - Oh my god.
温斯顿 你在干什么  把这个给我
Winston, what are you doing, man? Give me that!
- 怎么回事  - 发生什么事
- What's going on?  - What happened?
我不知道  他就站起来拿起枪然后他想...
I don't know! He just woke up and grabbed the gun and he tried to...
温斯顿  温斯顿 你还好吗
Winston. Winston, you okay?
它在生长...
It's growing...
在我体内
inside me.
我撑不下去的了
I'm not going to make it.
求你了  求你了
Please. Please.
别让我变成那些东西的...一员
Don't let me turn into one of those... things.
嘿 纽特
Hey, Newt.
谢谢你
Thank you.
现在 快离开这里
Now, get out of here.
永别了 温斯顿
Goodbye, Winston.
走吧
Go.
没关系的
It's okay.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
托马斯
Thomas.
照顾好他们
Take care of them.
我以为我们应该是免疫的
I thought we were suppose to be immune.
我想不是全部人吧
Not all of us. I guess.
如果温斯顿能被感染 我们应该假设我们都会
If Winston can get infected, we should assume so can the rest of us.
我从没想到我会这样说
I never thought I would say it.
我想念基地了
I missed the Glade.
起来  喂 起来
Get up. Yo, get up.
- 来吧 我们要走了  起来 费平  - 阿里斯 我看见些什么
- Come on, let's go. Get up, Frypan.  - Aris, I see something.
什么  是什么  什么
What? What is it? What?
看见了吗
See that?
是光
It's lights.
我们做到了
We made it.
- 我们走吧  我们要走了  - 好
- Let's go! We got to go.  - Yeah.
来吧  我们走
Come on. Let's go. Let's go.
- 快点  - 走吧
- Hurry!  - Go!
跑
Run!
- 一直跑 来吧  - 我们走
- Keep moving, come on!  - Let's go!
来吧 特丽莎
Come on, Teresa!
跑 跑 跑
Go go go!
我们越来越近了
We're getting closer!
继续跑
Keep going!
快点  快点
Come on! Come on!
跑进去  快跑
Get inside, go!
米诺
Minho!
嘿  嘿
Hey. Hey.
来吧 兄弟
Come on, man.
来吧 扶他起来
Come on, get him up.
- 跑快  - 继续跑
- Go! Go!  - Keep going!
快跑
Go!
跑  来吧 快点
Move! Come on, hurry up!
- 快点  - 进去
- Come on!  - Get in!
- 你刚说什么  - 谁有光
- What did you say?  - Who's got a light.
米诺
Minho!
别这样  醒醒
Come on, come on, come on.
- 米诺  - 米诺
- Minho!  - Minho!
- 醒醒啊 米诺  - 快醒醒
- Come on, Minho.  - Come on.
醒醒吧 兄弟
Come on, man!
你没事吧
You okay?
发生什么事了
What happened?
你被闪电击中了
You were struck by lightning.
噢
Oh.
来吧 我们扶他起来  小心慢慢的
Come on, let's move him. Nice and slow.
你能起来吗
Can you get up?
谢谢 伙计们
Thanks, guys.
嘿
Hey.
这什么气味
What's that smell?
哇  那里
Whoa! Over there!
我草
Oh shit!
我看到你们跟我的看门狗见过面了
I see you met our guard dogs.
是谁
Who was that?
退后  站后点
Stay back. Stay back!
你们看起来很糟糕啊
You guys look like shit.
来吧 跟我来
Come on, follow me.
除非你们想跟他们一起呆在这
Unless you want to stay here with them.
什么
What?
来吧 跟上  豪尔赫想见你们
Come on, keep up. Jorge here, wants to meet you.
谁是豪尔赫
Who's Jorge?
你会知道的
You'll see.
没有人从焦土出来很长时间了
No one's come out of the Scorch in a long time.
你刚让他很好奇
You just got him curious.
我也是
And me too.
我对这地方开始有不好的感觉了
I'm going to start to get a bad feeling about this place.
我们就听他说  看看他说什么
Let's just hear him out. See what he has to say.
豪尔赫 他们到了
Jorge, they are here.
你们有过全世界都跟你作对的感觉吗
Do you ever get the feeling the whole world is against you?
3个问题
3 questions:
你们是从哪来的
Where did you come from?
你们在去哪里
Where're you going?
我怎么能得益
How can I profit?
别一次性全回答
Don't all answer at once.
我们要去山上
We're heading for the mountains.
我们在找右臂
We are looking for Right Arm.
你意思是你在找幽灵
You're looking for ghost, you mean?
第2次问
Question number 2.
你们是从哪里来的
Where did you come from?
这是我们的事
That's our business.
放开我  放开我
Get the hell off me. Get the hell off me, man.
闭嘴 你这大婴儿
Shut up, you big baby.
这是什么
What is that?
你是对的
You were right.
什么是对的  她在说什么
Right about what? What is she talking about.
我很抱歉 兄弟
I'm sorry, hermano.
看来你被标记了
Looks like you're tagged.
你是来自WCKD的
You came from WCKD.
那就是说...
Which means...
你很有价值
you're very valuable.
很好的计划 托马斯  “就听听这男人说什么”
Great plan, Thomas. "Just hear what the man has to say."
- 这对我们真有效  - 噢  闭嘴吧 米诺
- Really working out for us.  - Oh. Shut up, Minho.
也许我可以...可以抓到绳子
Maybe I can... can reach the rope.
在欣赏风景吗
Enjoying the view?
你他妈的想要什么
What the hell do you want?
这是个问题
That is the question.
我的人想把你们卖回去WCKD
My men want to sell you back to WCKD.
生活教会他们别想太多
Life has taught them to think small.
我从来都不会这样
I've never like that.
有些东西告诉我你也不是这样
Something tells me you're not either.
是血冲昏我的头还是摇晃没有意义呢
Is it blood rushing through my head or is the shake not making any sense?
告诉我你们知道右臂些什么
Tell me what you know about the Right Arm.
- 我以为你说他们是幽灵  - 我相信有幽灵的存在
- I thought you said they were ghosts.  - I happen to believe in ghosts.
特别是当我听到他们在电波中喋喋不休时
Especially when I hear them chattering among the air waves.
你告诉我你知道的也许我们可以做个交易
You tell me what you know and maybe we can make a deal.
听着 我们...我们知道的不多
Look, we... we don't know much.
哇  哇  哇  好吧  好吧
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa. Okay, okay, okay. Alright.
他们藏在山里
They're hiding in the mountains.
而且他们攻击WCKD还有他们有一堆小孩
And they attack WCKD and they got a bunch of kids.
就这样 我就知道这些
That's it, that's all we know.
豪尔赫
Jorge.
发什么事
What's going on?
我和我的新朋友们只是在互相了解
Me and my new friends, we are just getting acquainted.
我们了解完了
We're done now.
嘿 等等  什么  你不是要帮我们吗
Hey, wait. What. You're not going to help us?
别担心 兄弟
Don't worry, hermano.
我们会带你们回去你们原来的地方
We will get you back to where you belong.
吊紧了
Hang tight.
要去哪里吗
Going somewhere?
我们都要去  拿上你需要的东西
We both are. Pack what you need.
悄悄地收拾
Do it quietly.
我们到底要去哪里
Where exactly are we going?
是真的 布伦达  这些孩子是我们的入场券
It's real, Brenda. These kids are our ticket.
我们是对的  他们不能把我们带走
We're right. They can't turn us away.
马上去
Go now.
好了  我抓到了
Okay. I got it.
- 米诺   - 是
- Minho.  - Yeah.
- 米诺 准备好了吗  - 来
- Minho, ready?  - Yeah.
抓住  好了
Gotcha. Okay.
1 2 3然后推
1, 2, 3 and go.
- 3  - 3
- 3.  - 3.
- 不够远  - 草
- Not far enough.  - Shit!
我到预定位置了  派他们进来
I'm in position. Send them in.
来吧 米诺  大力点推她
Come on, Minho. Push her harder.
草
Shit.
就这样  1 2 3
This is it. 1, 2, 3.
- 好  很好  - 好了
- Yes! Yes!  - Okay.
特丽莎 快点
Teresa, hurry!
那么就这样  你就放弃这一切  所有你建立的
So, what? You're just going to give it all up? Everything you built.
这里没有未来
There is no future here.
当另一帮人找到这地方会发生什么
What happens when another gang find this place?
我控制不了 我保护不了你
And I lose control, I can't protect you.
我不需要你保护我
I don't need you to protect me.
如果你感染了闪焰怎么办
What happens if you get the Flare?
我之后该怎么做
What am I suppose to do then?
锁上你看着你转变  向你的头开枪
Chain you up, watch you turn? Put a bullet in your head?
- 你是希望我这样吗  - 我为了你也同样会这样做
- Is that what you expect of me?  - I will do the same thing for you.
晚上好  这是灾变的世界：杀戮地带部
Good evening. This is the World In Catastrophe: Killzone Department
我们已经完全包围你们的地方
We have your compound completely surrounded.
你们会发现自己拿了WCKD的财产
You find yourselves, with no fault of your own.
- 是没有错的  - 巴克利
- The possession of WCKD property.  - Barkley.
平安无事的还给我们而我们会把这当作一个误会
Return them to us unharmed and we'll consider this a simple misunderstanding.
坚持着伙计们
hang on, guys
或你们可以抵抗
Or you can resist,
而你们每一个都会死
and every last one of you, will die.
在闪焰冲击我们剩余的人前不会有太多时间了
It won't be long before the Flare wash out the rest of us.
治愈的希望就在你们的手中
The hope for a cure lies in your hands.
由你们来选择
The choice is yours.
去带小孩过来
Go get the kids.
你要去做什么
What're you going to do?
我要去给他播我最喜欢的歌
I'm going to play him my favorite song.
我草
Oh shit.
我们走  我们走
Let's go. Let's go.
我们不想惹到任何麻烦 好吗  我们只是想离开这里
We're not trying to cause any trouble, okay. We just, we got to get out of here.
是这样吗
Is that so?
詹森 我给你抓住他们了  我现在带他们下来
Janson, I got them for you. I'm bringing them down.
别开枪
Don't shoot us.
来吧  我们走
Come on. Let's go.
我说 我们走
I said, let's go
你这小混蛋
You little bastard.
好了  来吧
Okay. Come on.
来吧 我们走
Come on, let's go!
巴克利 你位置在哪
Barkley, what's your location?
巴克利 你在吗
Barkley, are you there?
长官 你听到这个了吗
Sir, do you hear this?
这是什么
What is that?
布伦达  快点 我们没有太多时间了
Brenda! Hurry, we don't have much time.
我们走  我们走
Let's go. Let's go. Let's go. Let's go!
这边
Right this way!
- 噢 你一定是在跟我开玩笑  - B计划 埃尔马诺
- Oh, you got to be kidding me.  - Plan B, hermano.
你们想去右臂那  我会带你们去
You kids want to get to the Right Arm. I'll lead you to them.
但你们就欠我一个人情了
But you got to owe me.
跟我来
Follow me!
好吧  我们走吧
Alright! Let's go!
- 来吧  - 快去  所有人快去
- Come on!  - Go go go. Everyone go. GO.
走吧
Go!
- 来吧  - 来吧
- Come on. Come on.  - Come on.
所有单位 往里面走
All units, push in.
他们在顶楼  顶楼
They're on the top floor! Top floor!
收到  快走
Roger, move!
- 快走  - 快 阿里斯 快
- Go!  - Go, Aris. Go.
特丽莎 下一个轮到你  来吧
Teresa, you're next. Come on.
布伦达 你在去哪里
Brenda, where are you going?
你快点去  我随后就来
You just go. Go go. I'll be right behind you.
快点
Hurry.
阿尔法22在追  正在移动
Alpha 22 in pursuit. On the move!
布伦达 回应啊  你在干什么
Brenda, come on! What are you doing?
我们要走了
We got to go!
- 我拿到了  - 来吧
- I got it. I got it.  - Come on! Come on!
找掩护
Take cover!
我们走  快
Let's go. Go! Go!.
来吧 快点  我们没有时间了
Come on, hurry! We're running out of time!
这里 跟我来
Here, follow me.
来吧
Come on!
草
Shit!
哇  我们需要他们  你绕过去 我追他们
Whoa. We need them. You go around, I'll go after them.
在这里  在这里
Over here. Over here.
孩子 别动
Kids, don't move!
布伦达 我们在去哪里
Brenda, where are we going?
快点 歌快播完了
Hurry, the song's almost over!
我草
Holy shit!
来吧
Come on!
托马斯  快点
Thomas! Come on!
你没事吧
You okay?
没事 很好
Oh yeah, great.
不 不 不  我们怎么回去其他人那里
No no no. How are we going to get back to the others.
别紧张  我要带我们离开这里
Relax. I'm going to get us out of here.
给你
Here.
为什么你们要帮我们
Why are you helping us?
相信我 这不是我的主意
Trust me, it's not my idea.
豪尔赫似乎认为你们是去避难所的入场票
Jorge seems to think you guys are the ticket to the safe haven.
什么
The what?
你知道的  天堂
You know. Paradise.
不受太阳威胁 不受感染
Safe from the sun, free of infection.
据说右臂带小孩去那里已经好几年了
Supposedly the Right Arm's been taking kids there for years.
都是免疫者
The immunes anyway.
而你知道在哪里
And you know where that is?
不
No.
豪尔赫认识个家伙 马库斯
Jorge knows a guy, Marcus.
他曾经...
He used to...
他曾经偷运小孩上山
He used to smuggle kids up into the mountains.
如果豪尔赫出去了那就是他会带你的朋友去的地方
If Jorge made it out, that's where he'll be taking your friends.
- 如果他出去了  - 天啊 你问好多问题
- If he made it out?  - Hell, you ask a lot of questions.
你能就过来这里帮我打开这个吗
Can you just, come over here and help me with this?
麻烦了
Please.
这听起来不对劲啊
That doesn't sound good.
是啊
Yeah.
这下面他们会很疯狂
Down here they'll be full turn.
我们走吧
Let's go.
我想是这边
I think it's this way.
你想
You think?
有人生活在这下面吗
Do people live down here?
太阳风暴逼人到地下
The solar storms forced people underground.
豪尔赫说有很多定居点在这些隧道
Jorge said there's settlements all over these tunnels.
那豪尔赫呢  他是你的父亲
What about Jorge? Is he your father?
很接近
Close enough.
事实是 我真的不知道他是什么 他只是一直都在我身边
Truth is, I really don't know what he is, he's just always been there.
而我一直都按他说的去做 无论多愚蠢都会做
And I always done what he asked me to do, no matter how stupid.
那么你不觉得右臂是真的
So, you don't think the Right Arm is real?
我觉得
I think,
希望是很危险的
hope is a dangerous thing.
希望杀我的朋友比闪焰和烤焦的总和还要多
Hope has killed more of my friends than the Flare and Scorch combine.
我以为豪尔赫会比他们聪明
I thought Jorge was smarter than that.
该死的
Damn.
嘿 我觉得可能是这边
Hey, I think it might be this way.
布伦达
Brenda?
这边  看看这
Over here. Look at this.
什么  这是什么
What? What is it?
这他妈的是什么
What the hell is this?
我不知道
I don't know.
天啊
Jesus.
快走  小心
Go go go! Look out.
我的天啊
Oh my god!
来吧
Come on!
继续走
Keep going!
我们快到了 来吧
We're almost there, come on!
哇  哇
Whoa! Whoa whoa whoa.
来吧  这边
Come on, this way!
托马斯  快点
Thomas!  Come on!
好的
Okay,
- 走  快走  - 来吧
- Go. Go.  - Come on!
继续走
Keep going.
小心
Watch out!
你没事吧
Are you okay?
来吧
Come on!
跟我来
Follow me.
就在你后面
Right behind you.
快走 快走
Go go go go.
哇 哇 哇
Whoa whoa whoa!
- 好了  快走  - 来吧
- Okay. Go go.  - Come on!
布伦达
Brenda!
布伦达  你没事吧
Brenda! You okay?
没事
Yeah.
好吧  等一下  我去找下去的方法
Alright. Hang on. I'm going to find a way down.
布伦达  别动  别动
Yo, Brenda. Don't move. Don't move.
来吧  抓住我的手
Come on. Come on. Grab my hand.
不 不 不...
No, no, no! No, no...
托马斯
Thomas!
我会抓住你的
I'm going to get to you.
- 布伦达  - 我够不着
- Brenda!  - I can't reach it!
来吧  来吧
Come on. Come on. Come on!
布伦达
Brenda!
抓住你了
Got you.
我们可以从这下去  来吧
We can get down here. Come on.
你听到了吗
Did you hear that?
你没事吧
You alright?
草
Shit.
布伦达
Brenda.
是  是
Yeah, yeah.
我知道
I know.
我们就去找马库斯吧
Let's just go find Marcus.
好了  尽量融入吧
Okay. Try to blend in.
A区
你确认是这地方
Are you sure this is the place?
你来是参加派对的
You here for the party?
额 不是
Uh, no.
我们在找马库斯  这是他的地方 不是吗
We are looking for Marcus. This is his place, isn't it?
这是我的地方
This is my place.
你是马库斯
Are you Marcus?
马库斯不再住这里了
Marcus doesn't live here anymore.
你知道我们去哪里可以找到他吗
Do you know where we can find him?
当然  他在B区那边
Sure. Sure. He's over in Zone B.
- 好吧  什么是B区  - 那是他们烧尸体的地方
- Alright. What's Zone B?  - That's where they burn the bodies.
嘿 这样  有没有其他人来这找过他
Hey, look is. Has anyone else been by here looking for him?
一群跟我们一样年纪的孩子 里面有个女孩 深色头发的
Group of kids around our age, they have a girl with them. Dark hair.
你知道什么吗
You know what?
我觉得他们可能在里面
I think they might be inside.
给
Here.
喝这个
Drink this.
这是什么
What is it?
入场券
The price of admission.
喝吧
Drink it!
到你
Your turn.
好吧
Alright.
你们俩享受派对吧
You 2 enjoy the party.
也许我们应该分开找  看看找不找到其他人
Maybe we should split up. See if we can find the others?
嘿
Hey.
别喝其他东西
Don't drink anything else.
生活是有趣的
Life is fun!
布伦达
Brenda?
他们不在这
They are not here.
我们走吧
Let's go.
我们得继续找
We have to keep looking.
为什么
Why?
反正我们也找不到右臂了
We couldn't find the Right Arm anyway.
没有马库斯就找不到
Not without Marcus.
你的朋友都走了
Your friends are gone.
都完了
It's over.
现在只有我们了
It's just us now.
就尽量放轻松
Just try and relax.
放手吧
Let go.
怎么样
How?
像这样
Like this.
什么
What?
你不是她
You're not her.
布伦达
Brenda.
托马斯
Thomas.
不
No!
嘿
Hey.
- 有没有人看见你来这里  - 没有 你在说什么
- Did anyone see you come here?  - No, what are you talking about?
- 我们没有太多时间了  - 托马斯 有什么问题
- We don't have a lot of time.  - Thomas, what's wrong?
我只是  我要见你
I just, I had to see you.
我只是想解释在它...
I'm just trying to explain things before it...
噢  不
Oh no!
- 托马斯  - 就听我说 好吗
- Thomas!  - Just listen to me, okay?
无论你告诉他们关于我什么 无论你说什么
Whatever you tell them about me, whatever you say.
我只需要你知道 我必须要做的 好吗
I just need you to know, I had to do, okay?
你做了什么
What did you do?
因为我不能一直看着他们死
Because I can't keep watching them die.
在这里
Over here.
- 来吧  - 不
- Come on.  - No!
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
托马斯
Thomas!
嘿  嘿 你会没事的
Hey. Hey, you're okay.
嗨
Hi.
我们要停止像这样见面
We have to stop meeting like this.
欢迎回来 丑八怪
Welcome back, you ugly shank.
我建议你快开口 你这狗娘养的
I suggest that you talk, you son of a bitch!
该死的
Damn it!
我很抱歉 你们要离开我的房子
I'm sorry, you're going to have to leave my house.
看起来你一直玩得很开心啊
Looks like you've been having fun.
听着  我不喜欢伤害你
Listen. I don't enjoy hurting you.
好吗
Okay?
右臂在哪 马库斯
Where is the Right Arm, Marcus?
等等  这是马库斯
Wait. This is Marcus?
这孩子很快明白啊
That kid catches on quick.
嘿  你脑袋做过手术吗
Hey. Are you the brains of the operation?
我知道 你知道他们藏在哪里
I know, you know where they are hiding.
所以你告诉我而我就跟你做个交易
So, you tell me and I'll make you a deal.
- 你可以跟我们一起去  - 我把那座桥烧了很久了
- You could come with us.  - I burned that bridge a long time.
此外我还提出我自己的要求
Besides, I make my own deal.
是你教会我不错失任何一个机会的
You're the one who taught me never miss an opportunity.
他在说什么
What's he talking about?
我在说供给和需求
I'm talking about supply and demand.
WCKD想要所有他们能找到的免疫者
WCKD wants all the immunes they can get.
我提供给他们
I help provide that for them.
所以我引诱孩子进来...
So, I lure the kids in...
他们喝醉了他们玩得很开心然后晚点...
they get drunk, they have a good time and then later...
WCKD来了
WCKD comes in
他们从中再挑选出来
they separate the wheat from the chaff.
- 我改变我的心意了 兄弟  - 噢  噢
- I change my mind, hermano.  - Oh. Oh.
我很享受伤害你
I do enjoy hurting you.
说
Talk!
- 快说  - 好了 好了 天啊
- Talk!  - Okay, okay, Jesus!
我不能保证任何事  这些家伙很喜欢到处转移
I'm not making any promises. These guys like to move around.
他们在山里有个前哨站
They have an outpost in the mountains.
但它在很远
But it's a long way away.
你走到一半WCKD就来追你屁股了 你永远也去不到那里
You got half a WCKD on your ass, you're never going to make it.
靠11路是不行
Not on foot.
贝尔特在哪
Where's Berthe?
不要找贝尔特
Not Berthe.
好了  我想我们要靠走了
Well. I guess we're on foot.
- 蹲下  - 找掩护
- Get down!  - Take cover!
大家没事吧
Is everyone okay out there?
我们没事
We're fine.
有人知道枪手在哪吗
Anyone knows where the bloody shots came from?
是马库斯  他带我们去一个埋伏
It's Marcus. He led us into an ambush.
我们该怎么做
What do we do?
给 拿着这个
Here, hold this.
我们要转移他们的注意力
We got to create a diversion
你准备好扔出去
You get ready to jock it.
所有人  准备冲刺回卡车上
Everybody! Get set to sprint back to the truck.
和盖住你们的耳朵
And hold your ears.
准备好了吗  1
Ready? 1.
2.
放下来
Drop it.
马上
Now!
我说 放下来
I said, drop it!
站起来  我们走
On you feet. Let's go.
我们走  快
Let's go! Move.
- 往后退  - 别紧张
- Back up!  - Easy.
你们现在要走过这里
You need to get over here now!
- 来吧 走吧  慢慢走  - 别做傻事 走
- Come on, let's go! On your feet!  - Do not be stupid, Move!
慢点
Slowly.
阿里斯
Aris?
- 我的天 哈里特  - 我的天
- Oh my god. Harriet?  - Oh my god.
你在这里干什么
What the hell are you doing here?
索尼亚
Sonia.
阿里斯 你很幸运我们没有射你的屁股
Aris, you're lucky we didn't shoot your dump ass.
你在那还好吗
You alright there?
- 怎么会  - 额  发生什么事了
- How?  - Uh. What's happening?
我们以前一起在迷宫里的
We were in the Maze together.
我们没危险 伙计们  出来吧
We're clear, guys! Come on out!
我们没危险  下来吧
We're clear. Get down!
我的天 你还活着
My god, you're alive.
倒车吧 乔
Back it up, Joe!
我们带他们去基地
We're taking them to base.
等等  那么你们是怎么到这里的
Wait. So, how did you guys get here?
- 右臂救了我们出来  - 等等 等等
- The Right Arm got us out.  - Wait, wait.
右臂  你知道他们是谁吗
The Right Arm. Do you know who they are?
上车
Hop in.
他们一直计划这个超过一年了
They've been planning this for over a year now.
这都是给我们的
This is all for us.
你们很幸运找到我们
Guess you are lucky to find us when you did.
我们天亮就搬走了
We're moving out at first light.
- 文森在哪  - 我想在那边某个地方吧
- Where's Vince?  - Somewhere over there, I think.
谁是文森
Who's Vince?
他是决定你能不能留下的人
He's the one who decides if you get to stay.
我以为右臂应该是一支军队啊
I thought the Right Arm was suppose to be an army.
对 我们以前是
Yeah, we were.
这就是我们剩下的的人
This is all what's left of us.
很多好人的死才让我们走得这么远
A lot of good people died getting us this far.
他们是谁
Who are they?
他们是免疫者 在山上抓到他们
They're immunes, caught them coming up the mountain.
你检查过他们了吗
Did you check them?
我认识这家伙 阿里斯  我相信他
I know this guy, Aris. I trust him.
好吧 汤姆  检查他们
Alright, Tom. Check them.
嘿 老大
Hey, boss.
布伦达  布伦达
Brenda! Brenda.
怎么回事
What's going on?
布伦达  布伦达
Brenda. Brenda!
布伦达  布伦达 说话啊
Brenda. Branda, talk to me.
抱歉  抱歉
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
- 发生什么事  - 她是怎么回事
- What happened?  - What's going on with her?
我不知道  布伦达 你还好吗
I don't know. Brenda, are you alright?
- 布伦达  说话啊  - 搞什么
- Brenda. Talk to me.  - What the hell.
我草  狂客  我们有个狂客
Oh shit! Crank. We got a crank.
- 停手  - 不 不...等等 等等...
- Stop!  - No no no... Wait wait wait...
- 回退   - 听着  听我说
- Step back! Step back!  - Just listen. Listen to me.
好了 听着  这是刚发生的 好吧  她还没有危险
Okay, look. It's just happened, okay. She's not dangerous yet.
- 你们不应该带她来这里  - 我知道 我...
- Well, you shouldn't have brought her here!  - I know, I...
如果我们让狂客进来这里 避难所就持续不了一周
If we let cranks in here now, safe haven doesn't last a week.
- 放开我  - 退后
- Let me go!  - Step back.
好的 我明白  好吧
Alright, I understand. Okay.
我明白 好吧  就听我说 拜托
I understand, alright. Just-Just listen to me, please.
求你了 好吗  我告诉过她你能她
Please, okay. I told her you can help.
- 好吗  - 不
- Okay?  - No.
肯定有些什么你可以做的
There's got to be something you can do.
对  是有
Yeah. There is.
我可以帮她从她的痛苦解脱
I can put her out of her misery.
不  不要
No. No!
文森  够了
Vince! That's enough.
放开他  放开他
Let him go. Let him go!
她被感染了 医生  我们没有什么能对她做的了
She's infected, Doc. There's nothing we can do for her.
不  但他可以
No. But he can.
哈喽 托马斯
Hello, Thomas.
什么
What?
你认识我
You know me?
有意思
Interesting.
说得过去他们把你放进迷宫里了
Make sense they put you in the Maze.
虽然我必须承认
Although I must admit,
我很担心他们在你做了那种事后会杀了你
I was worried they'd kill you after what you did.
那种事
What I did?
我们第一次交谈时 你说你再也承受不了
The first time we spoke, you said you couldn't take it anymore.
看着你的朋友一个个的死
Watching your friends die, 1 by 1.
我们最后一次交谈 你给我所有WCKD
The last time we spoke, you give me the coordinates
设施的位置我 试验场所和实验室
of every WCKD compound, trial and lab.
他是我们的信息来源
He was our source.
没有他我们就不能拯救那么多人出来
We couldn't have pulled all this off without him.
带她到帐篷里
Take her to the tent.
给这些人拿些厚点的衣服
Get these guys some warm clothes.
- 小心点  - 我来搞定
- Careful.  - I'm on it.
这是我们起码能做的
It's the least we can do.
托马斯 来吧
Thomas, come on.
我们需要从你这取点血
We need to get some blood from you.
一开始我们就迷失了
In the beginning, we were lost.
我们唯一知道的是
All we knew for sure,
你越年轻 机会就越大
was that the younger you were, the stronger your chances.
你跟WCKD工作的
You work for WCKD?
很久以前了
Long time ago.
你知道在一开始 我们是有最好的目的
You know at first, we had the best intentions.
找出解药 拯救世界
To find a cure, save the world.
很显然你们就是关键...
It was clear you kids were the key...
因为你们是免疫者
because you're immune.
但为什么
But why?
最终他们找到了答案
Eventually, they found an answer.
由大脑产生的一种酶可以免疫
An enzyme produced by the brain could be immune.
一旦从血液中分离出来就可以成为一种有效的药
once separated from bloodstream it can serve as a powerful agent
减缓病毒的蔓延速度
to slow the spread of the virus.
那么你找到了解药
So you found a cure.
不完全是
Not exactly.
酶不能人造 只能从免疫者身上提取
The enzymes can't be manufactured, only harvested from the immune.
只有小孩有
The young.
当然这不会让WCKD止步
Of course that didn't stop WCKD.
如果他们有他们的方法他们会牺牲一整代人
If they had their way, they sacrificed an entire generation.
全都为了这个
All for this.
进化得出的生物礼物
A gift biology of evolution.
但一个不意味着我们所有人
But, one meant not for all of us.
这能给她多长时间
How long will that give her?
每个人都不同 也许几个月吧
It's different for everyone, a few months maybe.
但这只是延缓之计 不是吗
But, that's the catch, isn't it.
她总会需要更多的
She will always need more.
好了
Okay.
我们...我们出去外面吧
Let's...Let's go outside.
让她休息下  走吧
Let her rest. Let's go.
她会没事的
She'll be fine.
托马斯
Thomas.
你知道她不能跟我们一起 对吧
You know she can't come with us, right?
他是我的兄弟
He was my brother.
抱歉  你没事吧  你感觉怎么样
Sorry. Are you okay? How are you feeling?
你让我想起了他
You remind me of him.
他永远都能看到人最好的一面
He always saw the best in people.
他现今在哪了
Where is he now?
我不知道
I don't know.
当我们还是小孩的时候...
When we were kids...
我们被其中一个WCKD营带走了
we were taken in by one of WCKD's camps.
他们给我们做了一大堆测试
They gave us a bunch of tests.
他们不要我
They didn't want me.
可是他们想要他
They wanted him though.
他们甚至不让我道别
They didn't even let me say goodbye.
他叫什么名字
What was his name?
乔治
George.
这是查克
That was Chuck.
他是怎么死的
How did he die?
为了救我
Saving my life.
- 如有有任何事发生在她身上 我...  - 我知道
- If anything were to happen to her, I...  - I know. I know.
你进去跟她谈谈吧
You get in there, go talk to her.
我想现在是我欠你了
I guess I owe you now.
我希望奥尔比可以看见这一切
I wish Al could've to seen all this.
还有温斯顿
And Winston.
还有查克
And Chuck.
他们会为你感到骄傲的 你知道的 汤米
They will be proud of you, you know, Tommy.
是啊
Yeah.
嘿 阿里斯
Hey, Aris!
嘿 伙计们
Hey, guys!
我有点喜欢这孩子
I kinda like that kid.
是啊  虽然我还是不相信他
Yeah. I still don't trust him though.
嘿 特丽莎在哪
Hey, where's Teresa?
她上那里去了
She went up there.
嘿  你没事吧
Hey. You okay?
你在上面这里干什么
What're you doing up here?
只是在想事情
Just thinking.
那我让你一个人呆着吧
I'll let you be alone.
你还记得你的母亲吗
Do you remember your mother?
记得
I think so.
我记得我的
I remember my.
她是一个很漂亮的女人
She was a beautiful woman.
所有人都喜欢她
Everybody loved her.
在WCKD来之前她是我的一切
Before WCKD she was all I had.
当她生病了
When she got sick,
我不知道该怎么做
I didn't know what to do.
我只是把她关起来把她藏好
I just kept her locked up, hidden.
我以为她会好起来
I thought she would get better.
每天晚上她都会发出很可怕的声音就像...尖叫
Every night, she made this awful sounds like... screaming.
然后有一晚她没有叫了
And then one night, she just stopped.
终于安静下来了
It's finally quiet.
我去她的房间
I went down to her room.
发现满房都是血
There was blood everywhere.
但她只是坐在那里 很平静
But she was just sat there, calm.
她说她感觉好点了
She said she was feeling better.
我的愿景实现了 她治好了她的病
My visions were came, she had taken care of them.
她把她的眼睛挖了出来 托马斯
She took her eyes out, Thomas.
外面有上百万人在受苦
There are millions of people suffering out there.
有上百万个跟我一样的故事
Millions of stories just like myself.
我们不能背弃他们
We can't turn our backs on them.
我不会的
I won't.
什么...你在说什么
Wha...What are you saying?
我在说我要你理解
I'm saying, I want you to understand.
理解什么
Understand what?
为什么我这样做
Why I did it.
特丽莎
Teresa.
求你别反抗他们 托马斯
Please don't fight them, Thomas.
你做了什么
What have you done?
不要...
NO...!!!
好了下去吧 伙计们  包围他们
Alright drop in, boys. Round them up.
跑  快离开
Go! Get out!
把他们拿下
Take them out!
起来
Get up!
别动
Don't move!
托马斯在哪
Where's Thomas?
快点  拿弹药来
Hurry! Ammo!
你来掩护我们
You need to cover us!
弹药
Ammo!
嘿  你知道怎么用吗
Hey! You know how to use this thing?
掩护我  这可能是我们唯一的机会
Cover me! This could be our only chance!
布伦达
Brenda!
你这蠢货
You dumb ass.
干嘛 你这是想找死吗
What, you trying to get yourself killed?
我们现在必须走了 趁我们还有机会
We have to go, now, while we still have the chance.
- 我要去找其他人  - 不  不 你看看那里
- I got to go find the others.  - No! No, look out there!
看  你帮不了他们
Look. You can't help them.
文森 快点  他们太多人了
Vince, hurry up. There're too many of them.
我没弹药了
I'm out!
小心
Look out!
草
Shit!
好了 放我下去
Alright, take me down.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
你没什么能帮得上他们 如果我们不马上走
There is nothing you can do for them, If we don't move now
我们也好不到哪里去
we won't be much better off.
- 你们要马上离开  - 什么
- You guys got to go right now.  - What?
他们要的不是你们
They are not looking for you.
你们会安全的 但你们应该马上离开
You'll be safe but you should have to go. Now.
托马斯
Thomas.
我不能离弃他们
I can't leave without them.
祝你好运 小孩
Good luck, kid.
布伦达 我们要走了  来吧
Brenda, we have to go. Come on.
来吧
Come on!
我们走吧  来吧
Let's go. Come on. Come on!
- 你没事吧  - 没事
- You okay?  - Yeah.
B-4.
- 我们抓到多少人  - 差不多全部人吧
- How many did we get?  - All of them, give or take.
- 什么差不多  - 那个 他们失去了几个
- Give or take what?  - Well, they lost a few.
A-4.
A-6.
B-3.
- 托马斯在哪  - 我在这
- Where is Thomas?  - I'm right here.
我们走吧
Let's go!
托马斯
Thomas.
把他排到队里
Get him in line.
好了
Okay.
带她进来
Bring her in.
为什么你不跑
Why didn't you run?
我不想再逃跑了
I'm tired of running.
- 这是所有的人了吗  - 大部分
- Is this all of them?  - Most of them.
这就够了
It'll be enough.
- 开始装载他们吧  - 是的 女长官
- Start loading them in.  - Yes, ma'am.
好了 你们都听到了  我们走吧 带他们上去
Okay, you heard! Let's go, get them on!
哈喽 托马斯
Hello, Thomas.
我很高兴你没事
I'm glad you're safe.
- 搞什么  - 特丽莎
- What the hell?  - Teresa.
等等  怎么回事
Wait, what's going on?
她是跟他们一伙的
She's with them.
什么时候开始的
Since when?
噢 特丽莎总是一个很高评价的人
Oh, Teresa always has an amount of appreciation of the greater good.
自从我们恢复她的记忆这只是时间的问题
Once we restored her memories, it's only a matter of time.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我没有选择  这是唯一的出路
I had no choices. This is the only way.
我们必须找到解药
We have to find a cure.
她是对的  这一切只是为了达到目的的一种手段
She's right. This is all just a means to an end.
你以前是很理解的 托马斯  无论你怎么看我
You used to understand that, Thomas. No matter what you think of me
我不是怪物 我是一个医生
I'm not a monster, I'm a doctor.
我发过毒誓要找到解药
I sworn an oath to find a cure.
无论付出什么代价
No matter the cause.
我只需要多一点时间
I just need more time.
更多的血
More blood.
哈喽 玛丽
Hello, Mary.
我一直希望我们能再次见面
I'd hoped we meet again.
我很抱歉在这种坏境再相遇
I'm sorry it had to be under these circumstances.
我也有很多事情感到很抱歉
I'm sorry about a lot of things too.
但这不是其中之一
But not this.
起码我的良心是很清楚的
At least my conscience is clear.
我也是
So is my.
玛丽
Mary. Mary.
Mary!
玛丽
Mary! Mary!
放开我
Get off me!
玛丽
Mary. Mary.
Mary.
玛丽
Mary!
不要...
NO...!
玛丽
Mary!
不
No.
来吧 詹森  带他们上飞机 我们走吧
Come on, Janson. Load them up, let's go.
这些人  杀掉他们
All this people. Get rid of them.
我们走
Let's go. Let's go!
- 放开我  - 索尼亚  阿里斯
- Let go of me!  - Sonia! Aris!
退后  马上  所有人别过来
Get back! Now! Everyone stand back!
- 后退  所有人别过来   - 别开枪
- Back! Everyone stand back!  - Hold your fire!
- 所有人别过来  - 别开枪
- Everyone stand back!  - Hold your fire. Hold your fire.
- 退后  放他们走  - 托马斯 把炸弹放下
- Stay back. Let them go.  - Thomas, put it down.
- 放他们全部人走  - 你知道我不能这样做
- Let them all go!  - You know I can't do that.
托马斯 求你别这样
Thomas, please stop.
我跟他们做了个交易
I made a deal with them.
他们保证  他们保证我们会没事的 我们全部人
They promised. They promised we'll be safe, all of us.
好吧  我应该...我现在应该相信你了
Okay. I'm suppose-I'm suppose to trust you now?
是真的  这是她唯一的条件
It's true. It was her only condition.
闭嘴
Shut up!
一切都可以回到原来的样子
Everything can go back to the way it was.
托马斯  你真的想他们都死吗
Thomas. Do you really want all of them to die?
听她说的吧 托马斯  想想你在干什么
Listen to her, Thomas. Think about what you're doing.
我们支持你 托马斯
We're with you, Thomas.
不
No.
不要
Don't.
引爆吧 托马斯  我们准备好了
Do it, Thomas. We are ready.
- 不要回去那里  - 托马斯
- Not going back there.  - Thomas.
这是唯一的出路
It's the only way.
托马斯
Thomas!
我们要走了  快跑
We got to move! Let's run!
- 带她离开这里  - 来吧
- Get her out of here!  - Come on!
你没事吧
You good?
别动  把它放下 小孩
Freeze! Drop it, kid.
- 快跑  - 快跑 蹲下
- Run!  - Run, get down!
别动
Freeze!
真浪费
What a waste.
文森 快走
Vince, go!
蹲下
Get down!
我来帮你  我来帮你
I got you. I got you.
快离开这里  快跑
Get out of here! Go! Go!
快点 托马斯  快离开这里
Come on, Thomas. Get out of here.
- 我们走吧  - 快离开这里 跑啊
- Let's go!  - Get out of here, go!
蹲下
Get down.
米诺
Minho!
托马斯
Thomas!
不要
No!
米诺
Minho!
快跑  来吧
Go! Come on! Come on!
米诺
Minho.
来吧
Come on.
我们现在该怎么做
What do we do now?
现在我们重整我们剩下的人
Now we pick up what's left of us,
我们按计划进行带你们去避难所
we stick to the plan and get you kids to the safe haven.
然后我们重新开始 我想是这样吧
And we start over, I guess.
我不会跟你们去的
I'm not going with you.
什么
What?
我保证过米诺
I made a promise to Minho.
我不会离弃他而且我要去找他
I wouldn't leave him behind and I have to go after him.
嘿 小孩  看看你周围 好吗
Hey, kid. Look around you, alright.
WCKD刚重击了我们
WCKD just kicked our ass.
你想想你该去哪里
You think about where you're headed?
我没有要求你们跟我一起去
I'm not asking anyone to come with me.
托马斯 听我说
Thomas, listen to me.
我认识了米诺...
I've known Minho for...
从我有记忆以来已经很长时间了
for as long as I can remember.
所以如果有任何方法...我们可以救他  相信我
So, If there's anyway... we can help him. Trust me.
我会在那里跟你一起
I will be up there standing next to you.
你在说的这个...
This, what you're talking about...
是不可能的
is impossible.
更像是自杀
More like suicide.
也许吧
Maybe.
但我现在知道我应该做什么了
But I know what I'm suppose to do now.
这不只是为了米诺  是为了我们所有人
It's no just about Minho. It's about all of us.
这是关乎所有WCKD没带走的人 所有他们会带走的人
It's about everyone WCKD's ever taken, everyone they will take.
他们永远也不会停止
They'll never stop.
他们永远也不会停止  所以我必须去阻止他们
They'll never stop. So, I'm going to stop them.
我要去杀了那个死婊子
I'm going to kill that bitch.
我必须承认
I have to admit.
我喜欢复仇
I like some revenge.
这演讲很好 小孩
Well, that's a good speech, kid.
那么你的计划是什么
So what's your plan?